Finding Aid for Engineering Science and Management War Training Program (University of Michigan) records, 1940-1945
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Engineering Science and Management War Training Program (University of Michigan) records 1940-1945
University of Michigan. Engineering Science and Management War Training Program.
23 linear feet
87188 Bimu E27 O.1 2
Records, 1940-1945, of the Engineering Science and Management War Training Program at the University of Michigan during World War II. Includes diaries, August 1941-August 1945, of Robert H. Sherlock, coordinator of the program.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from donor no. 2871.
The record group is open without restriction.
Set up in 1941 by Robert B. Sherlock, the program trained more than 12,500 men and women for immediate service to industry and local governments during its five-year existence. Courses included aircraft inspection, aerial bombardment protection of cities, ordinance materials inspection, industrial water supply and treatment, all taught by faculty members
Records include the programs for each year, a trainee file, and the diaries of Sherlock during the time he served as coordinator, 1941-1945.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Engineering Science and Management War Training Program.; World War, 1939-1945--Education and the war.; World War, 1939-1945--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Contributors:
Sherlock, Robert Henry.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Diaries
  - Diaries of Robert Sherlock, 1941-1945 (Box 1)
- Records
  - Engineering Training Program, 1940-1941 (Box 2-3)
  - Engineering Science and Management Defense Training Program, 1941-1942 (Box 4-7)
  - Engineering Science and Management War Training Program, 1942-1945
    - 1942-1943 (Box 8-13)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 14-17)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 18-20)
  - Ordnance Materials Inspection Course, Student File (Box 21)
  - Trainee File (Box 22)
  - Ivan Crawford file (Box 23)